Harshvardhan Patil

↑ harshvardhanpatil | in Linkedin | ► harshpatil1606@gmail.com | -44 7776532469

About

Dedicated and proactive Software Developer with 3 years of professional experience at one of the Big Four accounting firms, where I specialized in full stack application development. Currently, advancing my expertise by pursuing an MSc in Advanced Computer Science, with an expected graduation date of September 2024. Keen on leveraging my deep technical skills and industry experience to contribute effectively in a challenging environment.

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: ReactJS, NodeJS, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, Fast API, .NET, Django, ORM, Java, Spring Framework
- Data Engineering: Apache Spark, Hadoop
- Cloud: Azure Cloud Services, AWS
- Visualization: D3JS, Apex Charts, High Charts, Tableau
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, Visual Studio, VS code, GitHub, Postman
- Others: Problem-solving, Attention to detail, Communication and teamwork

Professional Work Experience

Senior Associate - PwC, India (Product and Innovation Team)

Sept 2020 - Aug 2023

- Developed high-performance web dashboards with complex visualizations, managing and summarizing data across up to 50M records using React JS, D3.js and Apex Charts.
- Implemented Azure Function Apps with orchestrator functions to process outputs from diverse machine learning models, enhancing core application functionalities.
- Designed, developed, and maintained scalable backend and frontend services using Node.js and React, ensuring robust application performance.
- Led initiatives to increase cross platform support for workflow based applications and reusable D3 based components which where largely used across the firm.
- Performed data cleaning and analytics tasks using Python, optimizing data usability for business intelligence.
- Pioneered the adoption of Microsoft Power Apps and Power Pages, deploying innovative client solutions using low-code/no-code methodologies.

Intern - Padmajeet Infotech, India (Android and Java Developer)

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

- Developed and optimized features for a native Android application, improving user interface and experience worked on key functionalities on one of the E-commerce application.
- Assisted in backend development using Apache Tomcat and Java, implementing ORM for efficient data handling.
- Contributed to all phases of the Agile development process, enhancing project delivery and team collaboration.
- Ensured code quality and system scalability by adhering to enterprise-level standards and conducting thorough testing.

EDUCATION

2023 - present	MSc Advanced Computer Science at Newcastle University	
2016 - 2020	B.E. in Computer Science at Visvesvaraya Technological University	(CGPA: 7.17)
2014 - 2016	Class 12th Science with Computer Science Major at Alvas College	(84 Perc.)

RECENT PROJECTS

• Secure Chat Application

Acedemic Group Project

This chat application had functionalities like E2E encryption, Secure File Transfer, OAuth 2.0, instant message sharing, etc. security was taken as the top most priority in development of this application. Various technologies like FastAPI, websockets, React, Reddis, PostgreSQL where used.

• Premier League Prediction Application

DurHack Hackathon Project

Developed a software application for predicting Premier League football match outcomes using predictive analytics and machine learning. Project uses technologies like FastAPI, Rabbit MQ, ReactJS, Machine Learning, Prostgre SQL, etc.

• Driver Vigilance System

Deep Learning and Computer Vision Project

Developed a system to enhance road safety by detecting risky driver behaviors using deep learning and computer vision. Responsibilities included implementing and fine-tuning convolutional neural networks, preprocessing data, designing a user interface, and evaluating model performance. Technologies used: Python, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Scikit-learn

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

• Winner - Smart India Hackathon (Aug 2020) Team Leader

Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (Govt. of India)

Led Team ABHYUDAY to victory in Smart India Hackathon, one of India's largest hackathons, endorsed by the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare. Developed an Android application designed to improve response times and services in medical emergencies, addressing problem statement SS-42. Engineered and deployed the application over a challenging 3-day period, focusing on reliable functionality under high-stress, emergency conditions.

• 4th Place - Eyantra Robotics Competition (Mar 2019) Team Member

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

Secured 4th place in the nationwide Eyantra Robotics hackathon hosted by IIT Bombay. Collaborated in a team to design and build a robot for the Nutty Squirrel challenge over a six-month period. Engineered a solution that demonstrated innovative robotics applications in simulated real-world problem-solving.

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals	Issued Apr 2023
• PwC Certified: Digital Acumen	Issued Oct 2020
• PwC Certified: Human-Centered Design	Issued Oct 2020
• HackerRank Certified - Python (Basic) Certificate	Issued Sep 2020

Last updated: August 24, 2024